Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Moe, Eric, May 2014- ongoing; cuid5862; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  The website documents his work as a composer and performer. It contains information about his compositions and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files, a discography of his published albums, a biography of the artist, reviews of his performances and pieces, and a recorded interview with Moe in an embedded video file. He plays the piano and keyboard, composing classically-styled pieces that rely on rhythmic propulsion and innovative use of traditional instruments. Capture of the site began in May 2014. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Monk, Meredith, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  New site crawls are accrued semianually.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.meredithmonk.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the singer and composer Meredith Monk, information about her works and projects, a calendar of her events, examples of her works in the form of embedded video files, and information about workshops Monk runs. The compositions featured on the site are film and theater scores as well as operas. Site capture began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Montgomery, Jessie, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.jessiemontgomery.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Soundcloud audio and Youtube video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography and images of violinist and composer Jessie Montgomery, information about her works and projects, including that with the Catalyst Quartet, a calendar of her events, examples of her works in the form of embedded audio and video files, and information about taking classes with Montgomery. The compositions featured on the site are classically-influenced instrumental pieces, intended primarily for string instruments. Site capture began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
  Catalyst Quartet
- Moon, Beata, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.beatamoon.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, press articles related to her work, information about her compositions, and images of Moon. The musical works on the site feature Moon's piano playing as well as chamber and orchestral pieces. Capture of the site began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Moore, Carman, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5894; 3 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.carmanmoore.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website documents Moore's work as a composer of theater, film, chamber, symphony, pop, dance, and opera music. The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his works, images and embedded video files of the artist and his performances, reviews of Moore and his works, information about upcoming events, and prose works by the artist. Moore's work as a musician spans many genres. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the June 2017 capture of the site.
- Moorefield, Virgil, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.virgilmoorefield.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, press articles related to his work, information about his compositions, examples of Moorefield's musical and prose works in the form of embedded video files and excerpts from his book, and a calendar of his events. The compositions featured on his site make use of percussion and electronic instruments as well as non-instrumental media to create interactive and improvisational pieces. Capture of the site began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Mori, Ikue, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.ikuemori.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography and images of the artist, information about her compositions, including a discography of her published works, examples of her works in the form of embedded audio files, and a calendar of her events. The pieces featured on the site are improvisational computer music. Capture of the site began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Mostel, Raphael, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.mostel.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions, and examples of Mostel's prose writings. The pieces featured on the site are classically-influenced orchestra and opera music. Capture of the site began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Muchmore, Pat, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.patmuchmore.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a calendar of his events, and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a cellist and composer of classically-influenced punk music, and his work as a member of the group Anti-Social Music. Capture of the site began in April 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
  Anti-Social Music (Musical group)
- Mumma, Gordon, August 2015- ongoing; cuid5898; 3 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://brainwashed.com/mumma/ and gordonmumma.blogspot.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  gordonmumma.blogspot.com/, an external site, was included due to its contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl.
  Flash audio files on the site were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website documents the life and work of Mumma, a composer and musician specializing in electronic music, the components for which are frequently home-built, and horn. The website contains information about his compositions, a biography of the artist, information about his past performances, including a recording of one such event in the form of an embedded video file, images of the artist, scores and examples of his works in the form of embedded image and audio files, and a bibliography of his published prose works. Mumma's music combines acoustic and electronic instruments, as well as computers, to create compositions for solo, concert, symphony, and chamber ensembles. Capture of the site began in February 2015. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Nagorcka, Ron, December 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.ronnagorcka.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Squarespace audio player files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, excerpts of reviews of his works, a calendar of his events, a discography of his published albums, and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer of electronic and acoustic music making use of traditional indigenous Australian instruments and techniques. Capture of the site began in December 2017. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Nathan, Eric, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.ericnathanmusic.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded video and image files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions, news and reviews relating to Nathan and his work, a discography of his published albums, examples of his music in the form of embedded audio files, a calendar of his events, and a gallery of images of the artist. The pieces featured on the site are classically-influenced orchestra and chamber music. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Nathanson, Roy, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5899; 2 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://roynathanson.net/ and https://jazzpassengers.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  https://jazzpassengers.com/, an external site, was included due to its contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl.
  This is the archived website of Roy Nathanson, a Jewish saxophonist, composer, actor, writer, and bandleader who has been a central figure on the New York downtown scene since the late 1970s, as well as being involved in experimental theater. It also contains the archived website of the Jazz Passengers, a quintessentially downtown ensemble that performs a postmodernist blend of jazz and vaudeville, of which Nathanson is a part. Capture of the site began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Neill, Ben, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.benneill.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded Spotify files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a calendar of his events, his blog, press relating to Neill, and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files as well as prose writings. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as the inventor and player of the mutantrumpet, a hybrid electro-acoustic instrument based on the trumpet, and a composer of instrumental music influenced by jazz, electronica, and classical styles. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site.
- Neuwirth, Olga, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.olganeuwirth.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her compositions, news relating to Neuwirth and her works, a discography of her published albums, examples of her prose writings, and a calendar of her events. The pieces featured on the site are classically-influenced orchestra and chamber music, as well as compositions for theater, film, vocalists, and installations. Capture of the site began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- New York Downtown Scene and other miscellaneous discographies, May 2017- ongoing; cuid5859; Roussel, Patrice, 1956-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://nyds-discographies.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains the discographies of composers Tim Berne, Anthony Coleman, Tom Cora, Dave Douglas, Marty Ehrlich, Ellery Eskelin, Fred Frith, Wayne Horvitz, Guy Klucevsek, Steve Lacy, Arto Lindsay, Chirstian Marclay, Ikue Mori, Lawrence "Butch" Morris, David Moss, Evan Parker, Zeena Parkins, Bobby Previte, Marc Ribot, Jon Rose, Ned Rothenberg, Elliott Sharp, David Shea, Otomo Yoshihide, and John Zorn. Capture of the website began in May 2017. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Niblock, Phill, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://phillniblock.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  he website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions, news relating to Niblock and his works, a discography of his published albums, and a calendar of his events. The pieces featured on the site are experimental and minimalist instrumental compositions in the avant-garde style. Capture of the site began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Niv, Yoni, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.yoniniv.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions, research, and teaching, and a calendar of his events. The pieces featured on the site are computer music in the new music style, mixing improvisation with scored performance. Capture of the site began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Pamies, Joan Arnau, 2014-02-2017-05; cuid5854; 2 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://joanarnaupamies.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Site crawls were discontinued in May 2017 because the site was taken down by the owner.
  The website documents his work as a composer and performer in the new music genre. The website contains a biography of the artist, examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files, a calendar of his events, and examples of Pamies' prose writings. His music combines traditional instruments with new techniques and accessories to create experimental performance pieces. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the May 2017 capture of the site.
- Parkins, Zeena, December 2015- ongoing; cuid5941; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.zeenaparkins.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, news, publications, and press relating to Parkins and her works, a list of her compositions and scores, a discography of her published works, and a list of ensembles she has been involved in. Parkins' music, played on traditional and electric harps as well as piano and accordion, has strong inspirations from rock, jazz, and free improvisation. Capture of the site began in April 2015. This description is based on the July 2017 capture of the site.
- Patterson, Michael, April 2014-July 2021; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://ninacyoung.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Pop-up windows containing embedded audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his teaching, compositions, and projects, a calendar of his events, his blog, a press kit, a discography and filmography of his published works, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer of music across a wide variety of genres, including orchestral, film and television scores, jazz, chamber, and jingles. Capture of the site began in April 2014. This description is based on the December 2017 capture of the site. In 2020, the website redirected to an index of the orginal website. The website ceased to exist on the live web in 2021.
- Pavone, Jessica, September 2017- ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.jessicapavone.com/ and https://jessicpavone.tumblr.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the composer and violist Jessica Pavone, information about her compositions and projects, a discography of her published albums, examples of her compositions in the form of embedded audio and video files, news and reviews about Pavone and her works, a gallery of images of the artist, and a calendar of her events. The pieces featured on the site are in a variety of styles, including jazz, chamber, avant-garde, and experimental, and make use of viola, violins, and voice, primarily. The crawl also includes captures of her tumblr blog. Capture of the site began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Payne, Maggi, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://sites.google.com/site/maggipayne/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about her compositions and projects, a discography of her published albums, news and reviews about Payne and her works, a gallery of images of the artist, and information about her awards, education, and credits. The compositions featured on the site highlight Payne's work as a flutist and electronic music engineer. Capture of the site began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Perich, Tristan, September 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.tristanperich.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Past calandar pages were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, a gallery of multimedia art created by Perich, and a calendar of his events. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work fusing computer music with more traditional instrumental forms. Capture of the site began in September 2017. This description is based on the September 2017 capture of the site.
- Pintscher, Matthias, October 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.matthiaspintscher.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded audio files were not captured due to technological constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, news relating to Pintscher and his works, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a composer and conductor of classically-influenced orchestral music. Capture of the site began in October 2017. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
- Previte, Bobby, November 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://www.bobbyprevite.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded image files and Youtube and Vimeo video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, information about his compositions, teaching, and projects, excerpts of reviews of his works, a gallery of images of the artist, a discography of his published albums, and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a drummer and composer of music featuring improvisation in the style of the New York Downtown scene, an experimental music movement popular in 1980's New York City. Capture of the site began in November 2017. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
  Latin for Travelers (Musical group)
- Prokofiev, Gabriel, November 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of https://gabrielprokofiev.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded PDF and image files, as well as Soundcloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, his blog, information about his compositions and projects, a calendar of his events, a discography of his published albums, quotes from press pieces written about Prokofiev and his works, and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files. The compositions featured on the site highlight his work as a DJ and composer of hip-hop, grime, and electro influenced classical pieces for independent performance and to accompany dance. Capture of the site began in November 2017. This description is based on the November 2017 capture of the site.
- Puts, Kevin, November 2017- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website.